<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Oldpages on Len Kiefer</title>
    <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Oldpages on Len Kiefer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Len Kiefer</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2015/08/23/annotated-data-viz-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2015/08/23/annotated-data-viz-1/</guid>
      <description>Annotated Data Viz 1    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   Annotated Data Viz 1   23 August 2015  Homeownership and the Jobs Outlook BELOW IS A VISUALIZATION of job growth and homeownership by occcupation. This viz details expected job growth by occupation compared to homeownership rate by occupation. This viz was originally published on Freddiemac.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2015/08/29/annotated-data-viz-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2015/08/29/annotated-data-viz-2/</guid>
      <description>Annotated Data Viz 2    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   Annotated Data Viz 2   29 August 2015  BELOW IS A VISUALIZATION of household size and composition and homeownership from the Census1 going back to 1980. With this visualization, we can see how household size and tenure choice (own vs rent) has varied by age over time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/02/28/house-price-trends/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/02/28/house-price-trends/</guid>
      <description>Recent House Price Trends    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   Recent House Price Trends   28 February 2016  National house prices rise 6.2% Freddie Mac released its full year 2015 house price index and an interactive data visualization. The seasonally-adjusted national index increased 6.2 percent year-over-year and is now 29.6 percent above the post-recession low, and just 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/03/05/what-the-february-jobs-numbers-mean-for-housing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/03/05/what-the-february-jobs-numbers-mean-for-housing/</guid>
      <description>What the February jobs numbers mean for housing    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   What the February jobs numbers mean for housing   05 March 2016  Resilient job growth SPRING IS ALMOST HERE, and housing market activity will start to accelerate as we enter the peak homebuying season in the spring and summer months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/03/09/week-in-charts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/03/09/week-in-charts/</guid>
      <description>The week (so far) in charts    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   The week (so far) in charts   09 March 2016  Mid-week chart update THERE HAVE NOT been a lot of data releases this week, but that’s no excuse not to get busy charting. I tweeted  out several charts so far this week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/03/10/mortgage-rates-gif/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/03/10/mortgage-rates-gif/</guid>
      <description>How I make my mortgage rates gif    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   How I make my mortgage rates gif   10 March 2016  Making a data viz SOMETIMES ANIMATION CAN BE USEFUL, though it is often misused. I’ve been tracking the week-to-week changes in mortgage rates, and animating with a GIF.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/03/13/the-week-ahead-housing-starts-and-housing-market-index/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/03/13/the-week-ahead-housing-starts-and-housing-market-index/</guid>
      <description>The week ahead: housing starts and housing market index    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   The week ahead: housing starts and housing market index   13 March 2016  The week ahead Next week there are several data releases but the two that I’m paying especially close attention to are the NAHB/Wells Fargo Housing Market Index (HMI) and Housing Starts, part of the New Residential Construction joint release by Census and HUD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/03/19/the-week-that-was-in-charts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/03/19/the-week-that-was-in-charts/</guid>
      <description>The week that was in charts    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   The week that was in charts   19 March 2016  This past week I tracked several data releases that give us an idea of the health and vibrancy of the economy and housing markets.
State employment trends positive Consistent with the national employment numbers  state employment trends are positive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/03/22/the-week-so-far-in-charts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/03/22/the-week-so-far-in-charts/</guid>
      <description>The week (so far) in charts    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   The week (so far) in charts   22 March 2016  Mid-week chart update With existing home sales, house prices, and new home sales being released, this is one of the busiest weeks of the month for housing data. We’ll catch new home sales tomorrow morning, but let’s catch our breath and recap what we’ve learned so far this week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/03/24/tight-supply-data-viz-remixed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/03/24/tight-supply-data-viz-remixed/</guid>
      <description>Tight Inventory: Data Viz Remixed    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   Tight Inventory: Data Viz Remixed   24 March 2016  Tight Inventory EARLIER THIS WEEK, Trulia published a post by Chief Economist Ralph McLaughlin called “House Arrest: How Low Inventory Is Slowing Home Buying”. The article analyzed trends in housing inventory.
Trulia broke housing inventory into “starter homes”, “move-up homes”, and “premium homes”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/03/30/real-house-prices-and-population-growth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/03/30/real-house-prices-and-population-growth/</guid>
      <description>Real house prices and population growth    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   Real house prices and population growth   30 March 2016  EARLIER THIS WEEK the U.S. Census Bureau released updated population figures for 2015. These data revealed changes in population across the country. Jed Kolko published a nice summary of these data, and it got me thinking about the relationship of population growth rates and house prices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/04/06/dot-plots-and-distributions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/04/06/dot-plots-and-distributions/</guid>
      <description>dot plots and distributions    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   dot plots and distributions   06 April 2016  We’re going to make this chart (and talk about it)
Wait, what is this?
Let’s pause the animation and look at the last frame:
This plot shows the distribution of metro area unemployment. These data are available here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/04/14/data-viz-occupation-wages-and-regional-cost-of-living/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/04/14/data-viz-occupation-wages-and-regional-cost-of-living/</guid>
      <description>Data Viz: Occupation Wages and Regional Cost of Living    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   Data Viz: Occupation Wages and Regional Cost of Living   14 April 2016  A new data viz TODAY THE BLS released data on metro level wages, employment concentration and regional costs of living.
I put together a quick plot and sent out the following tweet:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/04/23/the-week-that-was-in-charts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/04/23/the-week-that-was-in-charts/</guid>
      <description>The week that was in charts    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   The week that was in charts   23 April 2016  THIS WAS A BUSY WEEK for housing data. On Monday, the NAHB released the NAHB/Wells Fargo Housing Market Index (HMI), which tracks home builder sentiment. On Tuesday we got New Residential Construction from Census/HUD which gives us housing starts and permits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/04/30/vacant-housing-from-surplus-to-shortage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/04/30/vacant-housing-from-surplus-to-shortage/</guid>
      <description>Vacant housing: from surplus to shortage    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   Vacant housing: from surplus to shortage   30 April 2016  EARLIER THIS WEEK the Census Bureau released the latest Housing Vacancy Survey (HVS) data for the first quarter of 2016.
Much attention went to the homeownership rate estimates, which showed a decline in homeownership rates near a 48-year low.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/05/01/annotated-chartbook-tufte-style/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/05/01/annotated-chartbook-tufte-style/</guid>
      <description>Annotated chartbook, Tufte style    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   Annotated chartbook, Tufte style   01 May 2016  I finally got around to putting together an annotated chartbook, Tufte style, using the Tufte package for Rmarkdown. Check it out
Some screenshots: Screenshot 1 
Screenshot 2 
Screenshot 3 
Screenshot 4</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/05/04/house-price-data-viz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/05/04/house-price-data-viz/</guid>
      <description>House price data viz    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   House price data viz   04 May 2016  TO HELP UNDERSTAND TRENDS in house prices, I have a couple of data visualizations for the Freddie Mac house price index.
Viz 1: House Price Dynamics The first compares the quarterly and annual appreciation for house prices across the 50 states plus the District of Columbia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/05/08/visual-meditations-on-house-prices-part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/05/08/visual-meditations-on-house-prices-part1/</guid>
      <description>Visual meditations on house prices, Part 1: data wrangling    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   Visual meditations on house prices, Part 1: data wrangling   08 May 2016  Introduction THIS POST CONSIDERS recent trends in house prices. Thinking a great deal about house prices, I like to look at many different DATA VISUALIZATIONS of house prices, at the national, state, and metro levels of aggregation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/05/08/visual-meditations-on-house-prices-part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/05/08/visual-meditations-on-house-prices-part2/</guid>
      <description>Visual meditations on house prices, Part 2: sparklines and dots (animated)    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   Visual meditations on house prices, Part 2: sparklines and dots (animated)   08 May 2016  THIS IS PART TWO of my series of meditations on house prices. In our earlier post we covered the data collection, wrangling, and some useful transformations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/05/08/visual-meditations-on-house-prices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/05/08/visual-meditations-on-house-prices/</guid>
      <description>Visual meditations on house prices    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   Visual meditations on house prices   08 May 2016  Introduction This is a multi-part blog series on visual meditations on house prices. You can find the links at:
 Part 1: data wrangling  Part 2: sparklines and dots (animated)  Part 3: bubbles and bounce  Part 4: graph gallery  Part 5: distributions  Part 6: state recovery  Part 7: don’t cross the streams   and maybe more as I think of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/05/10/visual-meditations-on-house-prices-part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/05/10/visual-meditations-on-house-prices-part3/</guid>
      <description>Visual meditations on house prices, Part 3: bubbles and bounce    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   Visual meditations on house prices, Part 3: bubbles and bounce   10 May 2016  IN THIS POST I’m going to describe how to make some additional data visualizations of house prices and discuss a bit about what they mean.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/05/14/visual-meditations-on-house-prices-part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/05/14/visual-meditations-on-house-prices-part4/</guid>
      <description>Visual meditations on house prices, Part 4: graph gallery    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   Visual meditations on house prices, Part 4: graph gallery   14 May 2016  Introduction IN THIS POST we’ll collect several visualizations of house prices I’ve shared on Twitter the past few days and have a little discussion. In prior posts I’ve also included code for some of these graphs, and the others are mostly straightforward extensions of the earlier examples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/05/15/mortgage-rates-some-perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/05/15/mortgage-rates-some-perspective/</guid>
      <description>Mortgage rates, some perspective    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   Mortgage rates, some perspective   15 May 2016  Another mortgage rates animated gif IN THE PAST I’ve told you how I made my mortgage rates gif. In this post I’m make an extension that uses stop motion techniques to reverse course. We’ll end up with this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/05/19/mortgage-rates-and-the-fed-funds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/05/19/mortgage-rates-and-the-fed-funds/</guid>
      <description>Mortgage rates and the Fed Funds rate    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   Mortgage rates and the Fed Funds rate   19 May 2016  YESTERDAY THE FEDERAL RESERVE RELEASED minutes from their last Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC) meeting in April. The big news was that the FOMC still considered a June rate hike a possibility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/05/22/population-growth-housing-supply-and-house-prices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/05/22/population-growth-housing-supply-and-house-prices/</guid>
      <description>Population growth, housing supply, and house prices    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   Population growth, housing supply, and house prices   22 May 2016  EARLIER THIS WEEK THE U.S. CENSUS BUREAU released data on population and housing units for counties across the U.S. in 2015. These data reveal important trends in population growth, and help shed light on recent house price trends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/05/29/improving-r-animated-gifs-with-tweenr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/05/29/improving-r-animated-gifs-with-tweenr/</guid>
      <description>Improving R animated GIFs with tweenr    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   Improving R animated GIFs with tweenr   29 May 2016   .col2 { columns: 2 200px; /* number of columns and width in pixels*/ -webkit-columns: 2 200px; /* chrome, safari */ -moz-columns: 2 200px; /* firefox */ } .col3 { columns: 3 100px; -webkit-columns: 3 100px; -moz-columns: 3 100px; }  RECENTLY I HAVE MADE several animated GIFs, primarily using the animation package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/05/30/more-tweenr-animations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/05/30/more-tweenr-animations/</guid>
      <description>More tweenr animation examples    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   More tweenr animation examples   30 May 2016  IN THIS POST I WANT TO PROVIDE some additional examples of using tweenr and gganimate to create nice smooth transitions in an animated GIF. In this post we’ll look at an animated waterfall chart.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/06/06/visualizing-the-us-housing-stock/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/06/06/visualizing-the-us-housing-stock/</guid>
      <description>Visualizing the U.S. housing stock    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   Visualizing the U.S. housing stock   06 June 2016  IN THIS POST I wanted to share a few data visualizations I made using the American Housing Survey (AHS).
For this exercise I used the metro summary tables which you can download from American Fact Finder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/06/09/dataviz-remix-housing-trilemma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/06/09/dataviz-remix-housing-trilemma/</guid>
      <description>Dataviz Remix: Housing Trilemma    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   Dataviz Remix: Housing Trilemma   09 June 2016  A dataviz remix I came across some interesting analysis from Josh Lehner at the Oregon Office of Economic Analysis about the “Housing Trilemma”.
The Housing Trilemma, captured in the chart below is based on the following claim:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/06/22/make-a-dotplot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/06/22/make-a-dotplot/</guid>
      <description>Let&#39;s make a dot plot    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   Let&#39;s make a dot plot   22 June 2016  IN THIS POST WE’RE GOING to make an animated version of the famous Federal Reserve dot plot comparing the dots in March 2016 to June 2016. As far as celebrity charts go, the dot plot has to be up there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/06/26/week-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/06/26/week-in-review/</guid>
      <description>Brexit, State of the Nation&#39;s Housing, and home sales: the week in charts.    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   Brexit, State of the Nation&#39;s Housing, and home sales: the week in charts.   26 June 2016  IT WAS A BUSY WEEK FOR ECONOMIC AND HOUSING DATA. Existing and new home sales came out, the Joint Center for Housing Studies of Harvard University released their annual State of the Nation’s Housing, and the U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/07/01/going-off-grid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/07/01/going-off-grid/</guid>
      <description>Going off the grid    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   Going off the grid   01 July 2016  See you later I’m going to be away from the grid (web, twitter etc.) for a few weeks. Back later this summer!
  &amp;laquo; Previous Archive Next &amp;raquo;       &amp;copy; 2017 Len Kiefer with help from Jekyll Bootstrap and Bootstrap • • Follow @lenkiefer !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/08/09/trends-in-credit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/08/09/trends-in-credit/</guid>
      <description>Consumer Credit Trends    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   Consumer Credit Trends   09 August 2016  TODAY the NEW YORK FEDERAL RESERVE BANK released its Quarterly Report on Household Debt and Credit. These data come from the Center for Microeconomic Data based on credit records from Equifax.
R code for the graphs are posted at bottom of page</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/08/13/visual-meditations-on-house-prices-part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/08/13/visual-meditations-on-house-prices-part5/</guid>
      <description>Visual meditations on house prices, Part 5: distributions    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   Visual meditations on house prices, Part 5: distributions   13 August 2016  OVER THE PAST THREE MONTHS I HAVE MADE several new house price visualizations. In these meditations I’ll consider some recent graphs and provide R code for them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/08/15/trends-in-credit-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/08/15/trends-in-credit-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Consumer Credit Trends Part 2: Data doesn&#39;t drive, it&#39;s lucky to be in the car    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   Consumer Credit Trends Part 2: Data doesn&#39;t drive, it&#39;s lucky to be in the car   15 August 2016   .col2 { columns: 2 200px; /* number of columns and width in pixels*/ -webkit-columns: 2 200px; /* chrome, safari */ -moz-columns: 2 200px; /* firefox */ } .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/08/18/data-swarm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/08/18/data-swarm/</guid>
      <description>Data swarms: Your firearms are useless against them!    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   Data swarms: Your firearms are useless against them!   18 August 2016  AUGUST IS ALMOST OVER, and it’s nearly back to school season. And that means one thing. No, not that we’re about to get a chance to watch the #1 NCAA football program of all time dominate the gridiron (though that’s awesome too).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/08/19/mortgage-gif-8-19-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/08/19/mortgage-gif-8-19-2016/</guid>
      <description>Mortgage rate gifs: Week of Aug 19, 2016    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   Mortgage rate gifs: Week of Aug 19, 2016   19 August 2016  No code, just some gifs:
Comparing mortgage rates by week (2014, 2015,2016) Annotated history of mortgage rates   &amp;laquo; Previous Archive Next &amp;raquo;       &amp;copy; 2017 Len Kiefer with help from Jekyll Bootstrap and Bootstrap • • Follow @lenkiefer !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/08/21/maps-mortgages-and-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/08/21/maps-mortgages-and-me/</guid>
      <description>Maps, mortgages and me    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   Maps, mortgages and me   21 August 2016  IN THIS POST I WANT TO DOCUMENT some R code I’ve recently been working on combining maps and distribution plots. As I discussed earlier lots of interesting data will be released in the fall and I want to be ready for it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/08/23/us-pop-map-1790-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/08/23/us-pop-map-1790-2010/</guid>
      <description>U.S. county population: 1790-2010    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   U.S. county population: 1790-2010   23 August 2016  SOMETIMES YOU ACTUALLY LEARN SOMETHING from social media. Today on Twitter I happened across this Tweet via @kyle_e_walker:
Anybody want population estimates for every US county &amp;amp; metro back to 1790? Well, here are mine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/08/24/more-maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/08/24/more-maps/</guid>
      <description>More map visualizations    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   More map visualizations   24 August 2016  IN THIS POST I’M JUST GOING TO share a few data visualizations I’ve been working on today. For most, no code, but these build off my previous posts here and here so you can check there for hints and I’ll post some more examples with code later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/08/26/more-on-pop-distribution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/08/26/more-on-pop-distribution/</guid>
      <description>Density squared    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   Density squared   26 August 2016  WE ARE GOING TO EXAMINE THE DISTRIBUTION OF US POPULATION and make an animated gif combining a map and a kernel density estimate of the distribution of county population densities. Density of densities, or density squared.
We are going to use the same US County Population Estimates 1790-2010 we used in my previous post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/08/27/housing-market-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/08/27/housing-market-update/</guid>
      <description>Recent economic and housing market trends: August 2016    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   Recent economic and housing market trends: August 2016   27 August 2016   .col2 { columns: 2 200px; /* number of columns and width in pixels*/ -webkit-columns: 2 200px; /* chrome, safari */ -moz-columns: 2 200px; /* firefox */ } .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/09/02/consumer-spend/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/09/02/consumer-spend/</guid>
      <description>What we spend: Consumer Expenditures in 2015    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   What we spend: Consumer Expenditures in 2015   02 September 2016   .showopt { background-color: #004c93; color: #FFFFFF; width: 100px; height: 20px; text-align: center; vertical-align: middle !important; float: right; font-family: sans-serif; border-radius: 8px; } .showopt:hover { background-color: #dfe4f2; color: #004c93; } pre.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/09/10/job-openings-and-hires/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/09/10/job-openings-and-hires/</guid>
      <description>JOLTS! Job openings and labor turnover trends    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   JOLTS! Job openings and labor turnover trends   10 September 2016  IN THIS POST WE’LL LOOK AT recent job openings and hires data from the Bureau of Labor Statistics Job Openings and Labor Turnover Survey (JOLTS).
R code for selected graphs posted below</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/09/14/bev-curves/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/09/14/bev-curves/</guid>
      <description>Industry-specific Beveridge Curves    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   Industry-specific Beveridge Curves   14 September 2016  IN MY PREVIOUS POST we looked at the Job Openings and Labor Turnover Survey (JOLTS) data and plotted a Beveridge Curve. In this post I want to add some more code that allows us to plot Beveridge Curves by industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/09/22/week-in-gif/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/09/22/week-in-gif/</guid>
      <description>Data visualizations for the week of September 22, 2016    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   Data visualizations for the week of September 22, 2016   22 September 2016  IT WAS A BUSY WEEK FOR ECONOMIC AND HOUSING DATA this week. Below are some data visaulizations I made tracking key trends in economic and housing market data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/10/11/hmda-viz1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/10/11/hmda-viz1/</guid>
      <description>Distribution of mortgage loan amounts in 2015    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   Distribution of mortgage loan amounts in 2015   11 October 2016  IN THIS POST I WANT TO CREATE some data visualizations with R using the recently released Home Mortgage Disclosure Act (HMDA) data.
For this post I’m going to return to the 2015 HMDA that you can get from the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB) webpage and I discussed earlier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/10/14/gifs-10-14-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/10/14/gifs-10-14-2016/</guid>
      <description>Some animated gifs: Week of Oct 14, 2016    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   Some animated gifs: Week of Oct 14, 2016   14 October 2016  A couple of views of mortgage rates:
Mortgage Rates in 2016 This chart shows the weekly average for the 30-year fixed rate morrtgage.
Comparing mortgage rates by week This viz compares weekly mortgage rates (30-year fixed rate mortgage) by year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/10/20/homeownership-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/10/20/homeownership-history/</guid>
      <description>Visualizing the history of U.S. homeownership rates    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   Visualizing the history of U.S. homeownership rates   20 October 2016  IN THIS POST I WANT TO LOOK AT THE HISTORY OF HOMEOWNERSHIP in the United States. I’m going to go relatively far back in time, using Census data to compare the evolution of the homeownership rate by state from 1900 through 2015.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/11/03/visual-meditations-on-house-prices-part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/11/03/visual-meditations-on-house-prices-part6/</guid>
      <description>Visual meditations on house prices, Part 6: state recovery    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   Visual meditations on house prices, Part 6: state recovery   03 November 2016  Introduction HOUSE PRICES HAVE NOW RECOVERED BACK TO THEIR PRE-RECESSION PEAK, at least according to some indices. The Freddie Mac House Price Index, for example, surpassed its pre-2008 peak in the latest release for data through September 2016.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/11/21/consumer-price-viz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/11/21/consumer-price-viz/</guid>
      <description>Visualizing recent trends in consumer prices    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   Visualizing recent trends in consumer prices   21 November 2016  Growth in consumer prices RECENT DATA INDICATE THAT CONSUMER PRICES INFLATION is ticking up, though the overall pace of inflation remains below historical averages. In this post I’m going to create a few plots analyzing trends in the Consumer Price Index (CPI) published by the U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/11/30/hpi-gif/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/11/30/hpi-gif/</guid>
      <description>Comparing house prices, rents, other prices and incomes    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   Comparing house prices, rents, other prices and incomes   30 November 2016  HERE IS A GIF COMPARING house prices, rents, other prices and incomes:
And a static version with code.
In order for it to work, you’re going to need a data file with columns corresponding to the date and the data as described in the footnote (available from FHFA, BLS, and BEA).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/12/03/visual-meditations-on-house-prices-part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/12/03/visual-meditations-on-house-prices-part7/</guid>
      <description>Visual meditations on house prices, Part 7: Don&#39;t cross the streams!    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   Visual meditations on house prices, Part 7: Don&#39;t cross the streams!   03 December 2016  Introduction ON FRIDAY I MADE SOME ACCIDENTAL data art. I ended up with something pretty much useless, but kind of pretty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/12/04/recursion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/12/04/recursion/</guid>
      <description>Nested recursion: Loops within loops within data frames     --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   Nested recursion: Loops within loops within data frames   04 December 2016  Introduction I HAVE BEEN WATCHING SOME VIDEOS of Plotcon 2016. All of the videos I’ve watched are worth watching (check out the playlist), but I was particularly interested in this one from Hadley Wickham:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/12/08/10-ways-to-visualize-rates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/12/08/10-ways-to-visualize-rates/</guid>
      <description>10 ways to visualize mortgage rates     --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   10 ways to visualize mortgage rates   08 December 2016  Introduction IN ORDER TO HELP PEOPLE UNDERSTAND WHAT’S GOING ON with the economy, housing and mortgage markets I spend a great deal of time thinking about interest rates. Interest rates, specifically mortgage rates are very important to housing and mortgage markets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/12/10/global-house-price-trends/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/12/10/global-house-price-trends/</guid>
      <description>Global house price trends     --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   Global house price trends   10 December 2016  Introduction THE GREAT THING ABOUT SOCIAL MEDIA is that it helps put me in contact with people from around the world. I started up a conversation with Twitter user @benmyers29 who shared some recent trends in Canadian housing markets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/12/12/ribbon-rate-chart/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/12/12/ribbon-rate-chart/</guid>
      <description>Ribbon rate chart     --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   Ribbon rate chart   12 December 2016  Introduction LAST WEEK I SHOWED YOU 10 TASTY WAYS TO VISUALIZE MORTGAGE RATES, but I’ve got another delicious one for you. Y’all like ribbon candy?
As before we’ll create this chart with R.
The data The data I’m going to use are estimates of weekly U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/12/14/fix-a-dotplot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/12/14/fix-a-dotplot/</guid>
      <description>Let&#39;s fix a dot plot    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   Let&#39;s fix a dot plot   14 December 2016  IN THIS POST WE’RE GOING TO REVISE the dotplot code I posted that lets you take the Federal Open Market Commitee (FOMC) projections and turn them into an animated dotplot.
The problem is that the code I posted was for projections through June 2016 that only provided annual projections for 2016, 2017, and 2018, but the FOMC added 2019 in their September and December 2016 projections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/12/15/more-amazing-mortgage-viz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/12/15/more-amazing-mortgage-viz/</guid>
      <description>More amazing ways to visualize mortgage rates    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   More amazing ways to visualize mortgage rates   15 December 2016  IN THIS POST I AM GOING TO share a couple gifs displaying mortgage rate trends. Check my earlier posts here and here for other charts.
I don’t have time tonight to write up all the code for these, so I’m just sharing the images.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/12/17/see-data-speak-data-part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/12/17/see-data-speak-data-part1/</guid>
      <description>See Data, Speak Data Part 1: But I&#39;ve go so much to say!    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   See Data, Speak Data Part 1: But I&#39;ve go so much to say!   17 December 2016  IF YOU HAVE BEEN FOLLOWING along-welcome if you’re stopping by for the first time-you’ll have seen many different data visualizations that I have shared with you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/12/18/more-ways-to-visualize-rates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/12/18/more-ways-to-visualize-rates/</guid>
      <description>Even more mortgage rate visualizations    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   Even more mortgage rate visualizations   18 December 2016  Introduction WE ARE BACK WITH EVEN MORE WAYS TO VISUALIZE mortgage rates. A few days ago, I shared some ways to visualize mortgage rate trends and here I posted some additional gifs without the code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/12/19/more-tweenr-housing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/12/19/more-tweenr-housing/</guid>
      <description>Simple tweenr animations with ggplot2     --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   Simple tweenr animations with ggplot2   19 December 2016  Animations with tweenr IN THIS POST WE ARE GOING TO CREATE TWO SIMPLE animated data visualizations using R ggplot2, animation, and tweenr packages.
See this post about tweenr for an introduction to tweenr, and more examples here and here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/12/23/populous-metros-are-heavy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/12/23/populous-metros-are-heavy/</guid>
      <description>Populous metros are heavy!    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   Populous metros are heavy!   23 December 2016  I WANT TO SHARE WITH YOU a little bit of code to make this whimsical data visualization:
Make a simple map First we can construct a map of the lower 48 U.S. states and add a marker for each city.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/12/27/data-tables/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/12/27/data-tables/</guid>
      <description>Data tables are Viz too    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   Data tables are Viz too   27 December 2016  THOUGH 2016 IS NOT OVER YET I want to get a jump on my 2017 resolution: make better tables.
I’ve been re-reading this paper on the Rudiments of Numeracy by A. S. C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/12/31/year-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/oldpage/2016/12/31/year-in-review/</guid>
      <description>A look back at housing&#39;s best year in a decade    --   Toggle navigation     Len Kiefer  Posts Chartbook Resume About   A look back at housing&#39;s best year in a decade   31 December 2016  THE YEAR IS DRAWING TO A CLOSE and by many measures 2016 was the best year for housing in a decade. Back in May I shared some trends on housing markets in a Tufte style document.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>